原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 Giggles  Lynn_宁  Alex  一点都不酷  木浅
翻译：某羽 JohnnyG   校对：油炸电风扇 木浅薰
时间轴：Avis  今  霜露
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第六季   第十二集
最新海外影视剧下载
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
这是你最后一次骗爸爸了
You made a fool out of Dad for the last time.
-哈维  -鲍比
?- Harvey-- - Bobby
你滚出我父亲的房子
You get the hell out of my father's house.
我要么拿走那个东西
I am walking out of here with that thing in my hands,
要么明早把你的律所置于死地
or I am putting your firm in the ground.
-画是你的了  -你跟我说过那幅画
- Take the painting. - You told me that painting
是你跟你妈妈唯一的快乐回忆
was the one happy memory you had of your mother.
我今天填的每张申请表
Every application I filled out today
安全与保密信息
你受过任何安保训练吗
你是否曾被判刑
都问我有没有被判过罪
asked if I was a convicted felon.
我选了那个选项  没有地方会雇我
None of these places are gonna hire me after I check that box.
去法律诊所不是重回正轨的唯一途径
A legal clinic isn't the only way to get back.
你是在给我提供一份教书的工作吗
Are you offering me a teaching job?
-没错  -这很好玩吗
- I am. - You think this is funny?
想到我们的老师上周还在坐牢就快把我笑死了
Cracks me up that our teacher was in prison last week.
你想的从来只有
All you care about is proving to me
向我证明你该做管理合伙人
that you should be managing partner,
即使全世界的人都认为你不应该
when everyone in the world knows that you shouldn't.
所以如果你认为我会让你成为管理合伙人
So, if you think I'm gonna let you be managing partner,
那你真是脑子坏掉了
you're out of your goddamn mind!
有个学生告诉了他父母你进过监狱
One of the students told his parents that you were in prison.
我试着向他们解释  但...
I tried to explain the situation to them, but...
很抱歉  迈克
I'm sorry, Mike.
他们都要走了  唐娜
They're all leaving, Donna--
先杰西卡  现在又是迈克
first Jessica and now Mike.
他们是我的家人
They're family.
你一直说的像只有我们是你的家人一样
You always talk like we're your only family.
你得处理好和你母亲之间的关系
You need to go make things right with your mother.
迈克  你怎么在这儿
Mike, what are you doing here?
学校不是7点上课吗
I thought school started at 7:00.
课是开始了  只是带课的不是我了
It does. I just don't work there anymore.
什么
What?
怎么回事
What happened?
有个学生告诉家长我是个罪犯
One of the students told their parents I was a criminal.
他们去找了总主教
They went to the archdiocese, and...
沃克神父也没办法
you know, Father Walker had no choice.
你昨晚怎么没跟我说
Why didn't you tell me this last night?
因为我不想破坏你的兴头
'Cause I didn't want to step on your moment.
路易的邀约让你那么开心
You were so happy about Louis' offer.
你打算怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
我要花一天  享受我作为自由人的生活
I'm gonna take the day to enjoy my life as a free man.
明天
And then tomorrow...
我要再重新开始
I'm gonna start all over again.
七年前
雷在楼下等你
Ray's downstairs waiting for you.
我没叫他来
I didn't call him.
是我叫的
I did.
他拿了你的黑西装和过夜包
He's got your black suit and an overnight bag,
他会送你去火车站
and he's taking you to the train station.
唐娜
Donna...
你得去参加你父亲的葬礼  哈维
You need to go to your father's funeral, Harvey.
我不能  这里事太多
I can't. There's too much going on here.
听我说  你刚刚经历了丧亲
Listen to me--you just suffered a huge loss,
却还一副照常办公的样子
and you're acting like it's business as usual.
我是一副我有工作要做的样子
I'm acting like I've got a job to do.
哈维  如果你不为他哀悼
Harvey, if you don't grieve him--
我会以我自己的方式哀悼父亲
I will grieve my father in my own way.
你不会的
No, you won't.
你只会封闭情感  硬撑下去  但是
You'll bottle it up, and you'll try to move on, but--
她也会去  唐娜
She's gonna be there, Donna.
我知道
I know she is.
但葬礼的重点不是她
But this funeral isn't about her.
也不是你
And it's not about you.
是你父亲
It's about your dad...
那个你在这世界上爱他超过任何人的人
the man you love more than anyone in the entire world.
如果你不去跟他道别
And if you don't say good-bye to him,
你会后悔一辈子
you're gonna regret that for the rest of your life.
唐娜  你来这儿干什么
Donna, what are you doing here?
问题是  你怎么还在这儿
The question is, what are you still doing here?
如今
我给你定了早8点去波士顿的班机
I made you an 8:00 reservation to Boston,
所以你现在应该在路上了
which means you should be halfway there by now.
我错过了班机
I missed my flight.
哈维  你从不会错过班机
Harvey, you never miss your flight.
上次你说你错过时
And the last time you said you did,
也是在对我撒谎
you were lying to me then, too.
-唐娜  -告诉我
- Donna... - Please tell me
你不是改主意不想见她了吧
you didn't change your mind about seeing her.
我没有
I didn't.
那问题在哪
Then what's the problem?
我已经七年没见她了
I haven't seen the woman in seven years.
而上次
The last time I did--
我知道上次发生了什么
I know what happened the last time you did.
听我说
Listen to me.
每天  你都在这个世界里
Every day you go out in the world,
想办法赢一把
and you find a way to win.
你就是这样的人  你就做这个
It's who you are. It's what you do.
唐娜  这无关输赢
Donna, this isn't about winning.
是有关的
Yes, it is.
但这次这事并不是只关系到一个人
But it's not just one person in this case,
而是两个
it's two,
现在  你们都在输
and right now you're both losing.
如果我做不到呢
What if I can't do it?
那就别上飞机
Then don't get on that plane.
但那边的那个包
But that bag sitting over there
让我觉得你愿意原谅她了
tells me that you're ready to forgive her.
如果是这样  你只需要原谅就行
And if you are, then that's all you need to do.
诉讼双雄 第六季 第十二集
-纳森  -你还记得我
- Nathan. - You remember me.
我记得每个人  你来做什么
I remember everyone. What are you doing here?
我来是因为你去送简历时
I'm here because I may not have been there
我虽然没在诊所
when you dropped off your résumé,
但那里还是归我管的
but I still run that clinic.
我是来给你份工作的
I'm here to offer you a job.
-我不明白  -海克特・苏雷兹
- I don't understand. - Hector Suarez.
你应该也记得他吧
I'm assuming you remember him, too, right?
-他怎么了  -你走后
- What about him? - Well, after you left,
我把你写的文件捡回来了
I picked up your file.
我猜猜  你把他留在了国内
Don't tell me--you kept him in the country.
不  迈克  是你做到的
No, Mike. You did.
我还想"这人或许有天真能当上律师"
I thought, "Maybe this guy will become a lawyer someday."
然后去年我在报纸上读到了你的事
And then I read about you in the paper last year
才得知你没当上
and found out you never did.
你知道我两次假扮律师
So you knew that I faked being a lawyer twice,
却还来给我一份工作
and you're still here to offer me a job?
我本不会  但我看到了这个
I wouldn't be, except for this.
你说了实话
You told the truth.
就我看来
As far as I'm concerned,
这意味着你值得我冒险试试
that means you're worth taking a chance on.
你还真是个圣母
Wow, you really are a do-gooder.
我不是为你
I'm not here to do good for you.
是为了我的诊所
I'm here to do good for my clinic,
因为我能雇城内顶尖律所
because I'm hiring a partner-level attorney
能达到合伙人级别的律师
from one of the top firms in the city
还只付他倒咖啡的小哥一样低的工资
for the price of the kid who gets me my coffee.
你还有专给你倒咖啡的小哥
You have a kid who gets you coffee?
没有  付不起
No, we can't afford that.
但如果付得起  我会付他跟你一样的工资
But if we could, I'd pay him what I'm gonna pay you.
你来不来
So are you in or not?
什么时候上班
When do I start?
我从没见过你穿西装
I don't think I've ever seen you in a suit before.
哈维  你来了
Harvey, you made it.
我绝不会错过
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
哈维  听我说
Harvey, listen, um--
你不用说  我知道
You don't have to say it. I know.
-她也在  -不止如此
- She's here. - It's not just that.
她问她能不能为爸爸说几句
She asked if she could say a few words about Dad.
怎么  你要让她说吗
And what, you're gonna let her?
-哈维  -只要我在这里
- Harvey-- - She is not saying
她就说不了一个字
a single word as long as I'm here.
不  她能  如果你当着我孩子的面
Yes, she is, and if you make a scene in front of my kids
在我们父亲下葬时闹事
on the day that we put our dad into the ground,
我发誓一定把你打得屁滚尿流
I swear to God, I will beat the shit out of you,
因为她是我的母亲
because she's my mother,
我会让她致辞的
and I'm gonna let her say her piece.
哈维  见到你很高兴
Harvey... It's good to see you.
莉莉  我也想说我很高兴  但是
Wish I could say the same thing, Lily, but...
那就是撒谎了
I'd be lying if I did.
很抱歉你会这么想
Well, I'm sorry you feel that way.
不管你相信与否  我爱你的父亲
And whether you believe it or not, I loved your father.
他的离世让我很痛苦
And I am sad to see him go.
是的  我不相信
Yeah, well, I don't believe it,
我来也不是为了探望你
and I didn't come here to see you.
而是来纪念我的父亲
I came here to honor my father,
你就上去吧  说完你想说的
so get up there, say what you're gonna say,
快点把这事搞定
and let's get this over with.
哈维
Harvey.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我想跟你谈谈
I wanted to talk to you.
真不敢相信  太好了
I can't believe it. This is wonderful.
不知道今晚你愿不愿意和我一起吃饭
I thought maybe you wanted to get dinner tonight.
没有什么比与你共进晚餐
There is nothing I would rather do
更让我高兴的了  但是今晚不行
than get dinner with you, but I can't tonight.
真希望你提前给我打了电话
I wish you would have called.
我想打  但是
I would have, but, uh...
你没有我的电话号码
You didn't have my phone number.
是的
No, I didn't.
明晚怎么样
How about tomorrow night?
我没打算在这里过两
I wasn't really planning on being here two nights.
我的律所现在
My firm is in a...
正处于危险期
vulnerable spot right now.
哈维  今晚有儿童艺术展
Harvey, it's the kids' art show.
一年举行一次  我不能取消
It's once a year. I can't cancel it.
你知道吗  这真是太傻了
You know what? This is silly.
你这么大老远飞过来
You flew all the way up here.
不
No.
我们可以明晚一起吃饭
We can do it tomorrow night.
我猜猜  你接受了这份工作
Don't tell me. You took the job.
事实上  在今早之前  我根本
Actually, until this morning, I didn't think
没想到我有可能得到这份工作
there was a chance in hell I was getting this job.
听起来你有个做前台的朋友
Sounds to me like you had a friend at the front desk
把你简历放在了最上面
who put your resume at the top of the pile.
听起来我欠那个朋友一杯啤酒
Sounds to me like I owe that person a beer.
确认一下  那个人就是我
Just so we're clear-- I'm that guy.
我听得懂
I get the picture.
迈克  欢迎来到这间律所
Welcome to the clinic, Mike.
谢谢你  奥利佛
Thanks, Oliver.
-看来你跟奥利佛打过招呼了  -是的
- I see you met Oliver here. - I did.
-我们相处得十分融洽  -不错
- We got along right away. - Good, good.
开头很不错
Well, you're off to a good start.
我想现在就剩下告诉我
I guess the only thing left is for you
办公桌在哪了
to show me where my desk is.
对  就在那间办公室里面
Right. It's, uh, right inside that office right there.
我没想到我会有间办公室
I didn't think I was getting an office.
就因为我付得工资低
Look, just because I'm paying you dick
不代表我会不提供你工作必备的用具
doesn't mean I'm not gonna give you the tools for the job.
我的工作到底是什么  因为就我看来
What exactly is my job? 'Cause as far as I can tell,
我是这里唯一一个有办公室的人
I'm the only one here with an office.
所有人注意
Everybody listen up.
从今天起你们有新主管了
You have a new supervisor starting today.
他叫迈克・罗斯
His name is Mike Ross.
迈克来自皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所
Mike is from Pearson Specter Litt,
他懂的法律知识比你们加起来的都多
and he knows more about law than all of you combined.
所以  迈克说什么你们就照做
So, if Mike tells you to do something, you do it.
我无意质疑世界新格局
I don't mean to question the new world order,
但想问他的头衔是什么
but what is his title?
问得好  玛莉莎
Great question, Marissa.
负责监督你们的高管
senior individual in charge of you?
还有别的问题吗  我看没有了
Any more queries? I didn't think so.
好了  都继续工作吧  抓紧
All right, back to work. Let's go.
你当时说这么做是为你自己
You really weren't kidding
还真不是开玩笑的
when you said you were doing this for you.
没错
No, I wasn't.
我想办法用这点薪水给这个位置找人
I've been trying to get somebody in this position
已经找了十年
for this money for the last ten years,
既然我现在找到了
and now that I have...
就得好好利用起来
I'm gonna take full advantage of it.
那你现在最好回到自己办公室里
Then why don't you go back to wherever your office is
今年就不用再出来了
and stay there for the rest of the year?
因为我得忙着在这大显身手呢
'Cause I'll be busy kicking ass out here.
就等你这句话了
That's what I like to hear.
想在这里订个好座位应该找谁
Hey, who do you have to know around here to get a good table?
我的天
Jesus Christ.
是我眼花了
Do my eyes deceive me,
还是你长得真的太像我哥哥
or do you look just like my big brother,
只是更老更胖更混蛋
only older, fatter, and douchier?
感谢你注意到了  变成这样不容易
I appreciate you noticing. I put in a lot of effort.
说真的  哈维  你怎么会在这里
Seriously, Harvey, why are you here?
我认为是时候和母亲重归于好了
I thought it was time to, uh, make my peace with Mom.
哈维  太好了
Harvey, that's great.
这些年里你们的摩擦太多
But, uh, a lot has been said over the years.
你不能就这样出现在母亲面前
You can't just show up on Mom's door.
事实上我已经见过她了
Actually, I already did.
什么  什么时候
What? When?
我去了大学里
I went over to the college.
她今晚要忙着为学生举办艺术展开幕
She's having an art opening tonight for her students,
所以我们约好明晚在此共进晚餐
so we're gonna have dinner here tomorrow night.
那我肯定给你们安排座位
Well, then I will get you a table.
你要做的是
And what you're going to do
取消掉你预定的不管什么狗屁豪华酒店
is cancel whatever fancy bullshit hotel you booked,
你今晚得和我们待在一起
and you're going to stay the night with us.
马库斯  拜托  我可住在里兹大使套房
Marcus, come on, I'm at the Ambassador Suite at the Ritz.
别想拒绝我
Don't think of saying no
因为我会告诉凯蒂和孩子们你来了
because I'm going to tell Katie and the kids that you're here.
你们提供客房服务吗
You guys offer room service?
如果你说的客房服务是指
If by "Room service,"
提供纤丝奶酪和低盐全麦饼干
you mean string cheese and Triscuits,
是的  我们的确有客房服务
oh, yeah, we've got room service.
好吧  那就把我算上
All right, well, then count me in.
玛莉莎  是吗  我是迈克
Marissa, right? Mike.
我知道  新老板
I know. The new boss.
怎么了
What?
没什么  只是在我以前的律所
It's nothing-- It's just where I come from,
老板们从来不骑车上班
the, uh--the bosses don't bike to work.
我想这里不是皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所
I guess this is no Pearson Specter Litt.
这里不是  其实这正是我来的原因
No, it's not, which is actually why I came here.
我很高兴如此  因为你可以
I'm glad, because there are a lot of people here
帮到这里很多人  但我不是其中之一
who could really use your help, but I'm not one of them.
你不是还在上法学院的学生吗
Aren't you still a law student?
是一个自从到这里就没输过的法学院学生
A law student who's won every case I've had since I've been here.
不错  那么我想这意味着普莱斯一案
Great, so I guess that means you have everything under control
都尽在你掌控之中了
on the Price case, then?
-你才刚来怎么就  -我阅读速度很快
- You just got here. How did you-- - I'm a fast reader.
玛莉莎  我并不想在我上班的第一天
Marissa, I'm not trying to throw my weight around here
就指手画脚
on the first day,
但是根据她的资料
but according to her file,
普莱斯小姐错过了她的开庭日期
Miss Price missed her court date,
所以我需要知道你的计划
which means I need to know what your plan is.
我的计划是让普莱斯小姐解释说她是单身母亲
My plan is to have Miss Price explain that she is a single mother
住在一间好几个月来窗户破损
living in an apartment with a broken window
而且没有暖气的公寓里
and no heat for months,
他们还想要把她赶走
and they're trying to kick her out.
如果你只是要告诉法官
And if all you're gonna do is tell the judge
这不公平  你会输的
that it's not fair, you're gonna lose.
-你需要法律依据  -我有法律依据
- You need legal foundation. - I have legal foundation.
伯格诉柯西克一案
Berger V. Chozick--
如果重要的要求没有得到解决
tenants are permitted to seek injunctive relief
租户是可以寻求法令救济的
if vital repair requests have gone unanswered.
那么我希望你还有后备计划  因为
Then I hope you have backup, 'cause the attorneys
对方律师们在过去的六年里
representing the other side have kicked out
已经赶走了300名租户
300 tenants in the past six years,
也就是说他们有点真本事
which means they are not messing around.
我也是
I'm not either,
所以我请了普莱斯小姐明天3点来一趟
which is why I have Miss Price coming in at 3:00 tomorrow.
所以还有什么我可以帮到你的吗
So is there anything else I can help you with?
或者你可以
Or maybe you can spend some time
花些时间在别人的案子上
on some of the other people's cases around here.
路易  我需要你帮忙
Louis, I need your help.
-当然  怎么了  -泰迪・道尔来了电话
- Of course. What is it? - Teddy Doyle just called.
他遇到了紧急情况
He has an emergency.
所以是哈维需要我的帮助
So you mean Harvey needs my help.
-路易  -唐娜
- Louis-- - Donna,
有哪怕一个我该帮他的理由吗
give me one good reason why I should help him.
你不是在帮哈维  路易
You're not helping Harvey, Louis.
你是在帮律所  泰迪是我们公司的客户
You're helping the firm. Teddy is a client of all of us.
不  哈维说的很清楚  我和他没关系了
No, Harvey made it clear that there is no us.
路易  哈维正经历着一些烦恼
Louis, Harvey's going through something right now.
他那股无名火并不是冲你
His outburst wasn't about you.
你信什么是你的自由
You can believe whatever you want,
但哈维对我破口大骂  现在却连亲自
but Harvey lashed out at me, and now he's not even man enough
来求我帮忙的胆量都没有
to come to me to ask me for help himself?
我凭什么帮他任何忙
Why should I even lift a finger to help him?
因为他想和他母亲和好
Because he went to go make things right with his mother.
他之所以这么做是因为骂你给他的感受很糟
And he did it because of how he felt after he lashed out at you.
否则  他现在就在亲自处理泰迪的案子了
Otherwise, he'd be taking care of Teddy himself.
所以你到底帮不帮他
So you want to help him or not?
需要我做什么
What do you need me to do?
迈克  家里怎么乱成这样
Mike? What's going on?
瑞秋  你不是八点才到家吗
Rachel. I thought you weren't getting home till 8:00.
-已经八点半了  -我都忘了时间了
- It's 8:30. - I guess I lost track of time.
我一直忙着整理这些文件
I have just been buried in this paperwork.
看得出来  我们是被审计了吗
Yeah, I can see that. Are we being audited?
我找到工作了
I got a job.
我本来要立刻打电话告诉你的
And I would have called you right away,
但是从我走进法律诊所开始就一直很忙
but I've been swamped from the minute I walked into the clinic.
你在法律诊所找到了一份工作
You got a job at a legal clinic?
-迈克  这真是太棒了  -是啊
- Mike, that's amazing. - Yeah, it is.
是的  他们知道我的事
Yes, they know about me.
事实上  那正是我被录用的原因
In fact, it's the reason I got hired.
我猜猜看  他们很聪明得明白
Let me guess.  They were smart enough to appreciate
雇佣和你同样经验的人
they can get someone with your experience
要花比你贵十倍的价格
for ten cents on the dollar.
就是这样
You got it.
确切来说是3.5万美元一年
$35,000 a year to be exact.
也就是说
Mm! Which means...
我们现在就应该开始打包了
We should probably start packing up the place now,
因为我们肯定是住不起这里了
'cause we definitely cannot afford to live here anymore.
我愿意和你住在鞋盒里
I would live in a shoebox with you
只要你开心
if it meant you were happy.
我觉得你是说你愿意和我住在鞋盒里
Aw, I think you meant that you would live in a shoebox
只要泰餐店还外送
as long as the Thai place still delivered.
-还有寿司店  -当然了
- And the sushi place. - Of course.
-要来一瓶吗  -开玩笑吗
- Want one? - You kidding me?
在读《粉红女孩》第七遍以后
After reading "Pinkalicious" for the seventh time,
我需要六瓶
I need a six-pack.
哄他们睡觉的感觉很棒
It was nice putting them to bed.
等你一年365天每天如此之后再看感受吧
Oh, yeah, let's hear you say that after doing it 365 days a year.
我还以为大多数时候是凯蒂哄他们睡觉
I thought Katie put them to bed most nights.
是啊  我就是替她说的
Yeah. I was saying it for her.
谢谢你让我住下  马库斯
Thanks for making me stay over, Marcus.
也许明晚过后
Well, maybe after tomorrow night,
你能多来几次
you can do it more often.
也许吧
Maybe.
谢谢大家的到来
Thank you all for coming.
我是莉莉
I'm Lily.
我和戈登结婚将近30年
I was married to Gordon for almost 30 years.
但没满30年  而正因为如此
We didn't make it the whole 30, and for a long time,
有很长一段时间  我认为自己是个失败者
I considered myself a failure because of that.
但是戈登没有
But Gordon didn't.
在我们离婚几年后
A few years after our divorce,
我想要为婚姻出了问题向他道歉
I wanted to apologize for things not working out.
他笑了笑说
He just smiled and said,
"莉莉  你说什么傻话呢
"Lily, what the hell are you talking about?
我们在一起是有成果的
We achieved something together
是我们单独绝对达不到的成果"
that neither one of us could have done on our own."
我们的儿子...
Our sons...
哈维和马库斯
Harvey and Marcus.
戈登出门的时候  总会打电话回家
When Gordon was on the road, he would call home...
每天六个电话来询问他们
Six times a day to check on them.
他们晚餐吃饱了吗
Did they eat enough dinner?
他们作业做完了吗
Had they done homework?
马库斯考了多少分
How many points did Marcus score?
哈维拿到他舞会用的晚礼服了吗
Did Harvey get his tux for the prom?
戈登这辈子有太多值得骄傲的事情
Gordon was proud of a lot of things in his life,
但是什么也不能
but none of it compared
和他们相提并论
to how proud he was of them.
他俩就是他的一切
They were his everything.
不管他身处何地
No matter where he is...
我知道此时此刻他也还在守护着他们
I know he is watching over them right now.
-你来干什么  -做我的工作
- What are you doing here? - Doing my job.
这是我的案子  不是你的
This is my case, not yours.
不  玛莉莎
No, Marissa.
这是我们的案子  我们是同一战线的
It's our case. We're on the same side.
如果你听听我的话  也许能学到一些东西
And if you'd just listen to me, you might learn something.
-比如呢  -比如经验老道的律师
- Like what? - Like the ways
可能会对你耍的花招
experienced attorneys can trick you.
我才不会被耍  所以
I'm not gonna get tricked, so...
如果你不介意  我得去见我的当事人了
if you don't mind, I'd like to meet with my client.
我已经见过她了
I've already met with her.
我还没到你就见了她
You met her without me?
-什么时候的事  -半个小时前
- When did you do this? - Half hour ago.
你约的三点  所以我叫她两点半过来
You said 3:00, so I called her in at 2:30
因为我知道你不会给我和她见面的机会
because I knew you wouldn't give me the chance to meet her,
就像我知道对方律师
just like I know the other side
会趁你不在时去接近她
is gonna approach her when you're not there.
-他们不能这么做  -为什么
- They can't do that. - Why?
因为这样不公平吗
Because it's unfair?
-因为这是违法的  -只有她提起诉讼才算
- Because it's illegal. - Only if she pursues them,
这是不可能发生的  因为他们会找到
which she'll never do because they're gonna find out
她身上的薄弱点  然后他们会
whatever her weak spots are, and then they're gonna offer her
提出恰好适合她的要求
exactly the amount she needs to get by,
之后她就会接受
and then she's gonna take it.
如果她这么做  她最后会落得无家可归
If she does that, she'll end up homeless.
这就是我们需要为防止此事做准备的原因
Which is why we need to be prepared for it to happen.
现在  你愿不愿意一起处理这个案子了
Now, do you want to work on this thing together or not?
我很抱歉在你来之前
I'm sorry I didn't tell you
没告诉你她会致辞的事
that she was gonna speak before you got here.
只是我真的没有跟你坦白的勇气
I just didn't have it in me to have it out with you.
没关系  马库斯
It's okay, Marcus.
她感动了你  对吗
She got to you, didn't she?
我是为老爸难过
I'm sad about Dad.
没错  她用我对父亲的感情触动了我
And, yeah, she pulled on that string,
但是一个致辞不能弥补一切
but one speech doesn't make up for everything.
或许是不能
Maybe it doesn't.
但总得有个开头
But you have to start somewhere.
没错
Yeah.
我得动身回去了
I'm gonna head back home.
别这样  哈维  来家里守灵吧
Oh, come on, Harvey, come to the house for the wake.
我工作上还有些事情要做
I got a few things I got to take care of at work.
别瞎扯  哈维  你不是为了工作走
Oh, come on, Harvey, you're not leaving because of work.
是时候放下了
It's time to let things go.
我已经说过好多次暖器坏了
I complained about the heat not working a million times.
房东总是说他会修的
Landlord always says he's gonna fix it,
然而并没有
and then nothing happens.
我们没钱搬家  所以我只能凑合
We couldn't afford to move, so I was just making do,
但之后我的小家伙  他得了哮喘
but then my little guy-- he got asthma.
医生说为了防止污染物危害
The doctor said that we need to keep all of the windows shut,
要把窗户关好
keep out the pollution,
但是客厅的窗户
but the window in the living room--
已经坏了七个月了
it's been broken for seven months.
我儿子才三岁
My son is only three years old.
听着他晚上的喘息声
The sound of him wheezing at night...
都不知道他能不能熬到白天
not knowing if he's gonna wake up in the morning...
所以我想  既然房东眼里只有钱
So I thought, "Since that slumlord only cares about money,
那我不付房租了
"I'm not gonna pay rent
直到他修好窗户和暖器
until he fixes the window and turns on the heat."
我很抱歉  索菲亚
I'm so sorry, Sofia.
-这听起来糟透了  -确实如此
- That sounds terrible. - It is.
没有人该过这种日子
And no one should have to live like that.
但是违反租约  他有理由驱逐你
But by violating your lease, he has grounds to evict you,
这也是为什么你要
which is why you have to give him a check
把欠他的钱补上这个案子才能有所进展
for the money you owe him while this case moves forward.
我做不到
I-I can't do that.
你已经没钱了
You don't have the money anymore.
我得买毛毯  小型取暖器
I had to buy blankets, space heaters.
有几个晚上AJ呼吸非常困难
There were a couple of nights that AJ's breathing was so bad,
我们甚至得去街边的旅馆凑合
we had to go to a motel down the street.
别担心  索菲亚
Don't worry, Sofia.
我们不仅会把你的窗户修好
Not only are we gonna get your window fixed,
而且我保证  你也能保住你的家
but I promise you, you'll get to keep your home, too.
谢谢
Thank you.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你指什么
What are you talking about?
你刚刚告诉她你能解决她的问题
You just told her you were gonna fix her problem.
因为我会解决她的问题的
Because I'm going to fix her problem.
这不是重点
That's not the point.
即使你认为你可以让事情好转
Even if you think you can make everything better,
你也不能给委托人打这样的包票
you don't guarantee that to a client.
我告诉你
You know what?
或许你对这些人漠不关心  但我关心
Maybe you don't care about these people, but I do.
为了确保他们能保住自己的家
And I'm willing to fight to make sure
我愿意战斗  我也不怕告诉她这一点
they stay in their home, and I'm not afraid to tell her that.
这不是你关不关心的问题
This is not about caring.
外面的世界很现实  而且我告诉过你
There's a real world out there, and like I told you,
对手都是经验老道的律师
there's an experienced lawyer on the other side
在等着我们犯错
looking to exploit our mistakes.
如果你承诺太多而实现太少
If you over-promise and under-deliver,
你只会让他们在这场不公平的交易中
you're just making them that much more vulnerable
处于更加劣势的地位
to a shitty offer.
这就是商业低球效应入门课教你的东西吗
Is that what they taught you in Corporate Lowballing 101?
低球效应又称虚报价格技术
是社会心理学顺从技巧之一
什么
Excuse me?
你根本不在乎这些人
You don't give a shit about these people,
纳森和其他人
and Nathan and everyone else here
也许信了你的鬼话
might be buying your bullshit,
但我知道你为什么来这儿
but I know why you're really here.
我明白  你调查过我
I get it. You checked up on me.
我不需要调查你
I didn't need to check up on you.
你这种人的事迹我之前听的够多了
I've heard your story a thousand times.
你在你的商业律师事务所干不下去了
You couldn't hack it at your corporate law firm,
所以你就在这里委曲求全
so you're slumming it here until you can figure out
直到想办法回到你那个轻松的
a way to jump back into your cushy,
专门找工人麻烦的工作中去
stick-it-to-the-working-man job.
看来我说对了
I see that I'm right.
把留着你的聪明才智吧
So keep your wisdom to yourself,
因为我是来这里帮助人的
because I'm actually here to help people,
而不仅是提醒他们这世界有多残酷
not just remind them what a cruel world it is out there.
-哈维・斯佩克特办公室  -唐娜  是我
- Harvey Specter's office. - Donna, it's me.
哈维  你快到了吗
Harvey. Hey. Are you almost here?
你六点应该到会议室的
Because your 6:00 is in the conference room.
我还没回到纽约呢
I'm not back in New York yet.
-你是对的  唐娜  -关于什么事
- You were right, Donna. - About what?
如果我错过了他的葬礼
If I'd missed his funeral,
我永远都不会原谅我自己的
I never would be able to forgive myself.
祝你能和你妈妈言归于好
Good luck making up with your mom.
你怎么知道
How did you know?
因为你这一生中
Because you've never missed a flight
从来没有错过班机
in your entire life.
而且你会留下的唯一原因
And the only reason you'd stay longer
就是事情发展得比你预想的要好
is if things were going better than you thought they would.
谢谢你  唐娜
Thanks, Donna.
我不需要你道谢  哈维
I don't need your thanks, Harvey.
我很开心你能去
I'm just really happy you're there.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
她怎么能不知道呢
How could she not know?
-我挑勾了  -没错
- I checked the box. - You did.
但是  是我把申请表给纳森的
But I was the one who brought the application to Nathan,
而且他跟我说不要告诉任何人
and he told me not to tell anyone.
为什么
Why not?
因为他不想让他们来评判你
Because he didn't want them to judge you.
我本以为大家无论如何都会知道的
I would have thought everyone knew anyway.
为什么
Why would you think that?
因为《日报》上到处都是报道
Because it was all over "The Journal."
我们这里不看《日报》
People here don't read "The Journal."
我们看《赫芬顿邮报》
We read "The Huffington Post."
所以他们的想法都和玛莉莎一样
So what Marissa thinks is what they all think?
我不知道  但是无论如何
I don't know, but for what it's worth,
不管纳森是否叮嘱过我
I wouldn't have said anything
我都不会说的
whether Nathan told me to or not.
这不是我该说的事情
It's not my story to tell.
谢谢你  奥利佛
Thank you, Oliver.
不客气
Yeah.
你做了草莓派
You made your strawberry pie.
这是他最喜欢的
It was his favorite.
可能你忘了  也是我最喜欢的
Maybe you forgot it was mine, too.
我没忘
I didn't forget.
悼词很棒
It was a nice speech.
谢谢你  哈维
Thank you, Harvey.
哈维
Harvey...
我父母去世的时候
when my parents died,
我觉得在这个世界上我是孤身一人了
I felt like I was completely alone in the world.
我不希望你也有这种感觉
I don't want you to feel that way.
我想让你知道  无论你的生活中
I want you to know that whether you want me
是否需要我的存在
in your life or not,
你仍然有一个爱你的妈妈
you still have a mother that loves you
一直都会在你身边
and will always be there for you.
我知道
I know that.
哈维  节哀顺变
Harvey, I'm-- I'm sorry for your loss.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
-你把他带来了  -哈维
- You brought him here? - Harvey--
你居然敢把他带来
I said, you have the nerve to bring him here?
-他是我的伴侣  -这是你对每个
- He's my partner. - Is that what you call
你和父亲在一起时上过床的男人的称呼吗
every guy you slept with while you were with Dad?
别这么跟我说话  鲍比和我还在一起
Don't speak to me like that. Bobby and I are still together.
-你觉得我在乎吗  -你应该
- You think I give a shit? - You should...
因为这表明了我是什么样的人
because it shows what kind of man I am.
你就是个垃圾  你没有资格
You're a piece of shit. You have no right being here
在我父亲下葬的日子出现在这里
the day we put my father in the ground.
哈维  拜托  我们正要
Harvey, please. We were just about--
我不在乎我们要怎样
Yeah, I don't care what we were about to do.
你把他带来  就是对爸爸的侮辱
You spit in Dad's face by bringing him here.
没关系
I-it's okay.
莉莉  我要走了
Lily, I'll go.
我才不在乎你走不走
I don't care whether you stay or not.
不  我在乎  他要留下来
No, well, I do, and he is staying,
因为  你可能不愿听
because you may not want to hear this,
但是  你父亲很久前就接受他了
but your father accepted him a long time ago.
你知道吗  鲍比  你想取代我父亲
You know what? You want to take his place, Bobby,
随你便
why don't you go right ahead?
也许有天你会撞见她和别的男人在一起
Maybe one day you'll even walk in on her with another guy,
那时你就会知道我父亲的感受了
and you'll know exactly what my father felt.
唯一不同的是
The only difference will be
至少那个时候
at least then...
没人会要求我保密了
I won't be asked to keep the goddamn secret.
这里有什么好吃的
So, what's good here?
事实上  这里每一道菜都很好吃
Actually, everything's good here.
你常来这里吃
You eat here a lot?
当然
Of course I do.
这个
This...
这感觉有些奇怪是不是
This feels strange, doesn't it?
是的  有点
Yeah, a little bit.
我们从何说起呢
So, where do we start?
我想  就从我告诉你
I guess we start with me telling you
我已经准备好原谅你开始说起吧
that I'm ready to forgive you.
为什么是现在
Why now?
有个对我十分特别的人说服了我
Someone very special to me convinced me that I needed to.
不管她是谁
Whoever it is...
我很高兴她这么做
I'm glad she did.
很好
That's good.
我想让你知道
I want you to know...
我也原谅你了
that I forgive you, too.
原谅我  原谅我什么
Forgive me? For what?
原谅我最后一次见你时发生的事
For the last time I saw you
以及你消失了这么多年
and for you being gone all those years.
我消失是有原因的
I had my reasons to be gone.
是的  在你年轻的时候你有原因
Yes, you did, when you were younger,
但你不是个小孩子了
but you're not a child anymore,
你早就不是小孩子了
and you haven't been for a long time.
真是难以置信
I can't believe you.
你居然还倒打一耙
You're turning this around on me?
我没有倒打一耙  哈维
I'm not turning it around, Harvey.
你根本无法想象自己的孩子
You have no idea what it's like to have a child
假装自己不存在的感受
who acts like you don't even exist.
你也无法想象自己的母亲
You don't know what it's like to have a mother
要求自己替她向父亲说谎的感受
who asks you to lie to his own father for her.
哈维  我确实不该那么做
Harvey, I never should have done that,
这二十年来我都在努力告诉你
and I have been trying to tell you
为此我真的很抱歉
I am sorry about it for 20 years,
但昨天之前  你都让我清楚的感到
but until yesterday, you made it clear to me
你对我的死活根本毫不关心
that you had no interest in whether I lived or died.
-因为我的确不关心  -你无法理解
- Because I didn't. - Well, can't you understand
这会伤透一个人的心吗
how that could devastate a person?
我至少可以理解我们见面是个错误
I can understand how this was just a mistake,
因为你还是以前那个自私自利的
because you are the same selfish, self-centered,
不忠的女人
disloyal woman you always were.
你也还是以前那个
And you are the same self-absorbed,
自以为是  小孩子脾气的人
childish man you always were.
那是谁的错
Well, whose fault is that?
又来了  你又要走了
Oh. There you go. Leave.
这是你的专长
That's what you do best.
你说什么
What'd you just say to me?
我说你也应该照照镜子  哈维
I said take a look in the mirror, Harvey,
或许过去我的确忽视了我的家庭
because I may have neglected my family in the past,
但你一直都在这么做  直到今天
but you've been doing it for as long as I can remember.
明天我该跟孩子们怎么说
So what am I supposed to tell the kids in the morning?
告诉他们我回纽约有急事
You tell them I've got business back in New York.
你要我为你说谎
You want me to lie for you?
马库斯  她居然好意思跟我说
God damn it, Marcus, she had the nerve to say
我应该向她道歉
that I owed her an apology.
要是她来了  告诉她我没什么好说的了
If that's her, you tell her I've got nothing more to say.
我告诉你  哈维
You know what, Harvey?
要说你自己跟她说
You can tell her yourself,
因为我不想再夹在你们俩中间了
because I'm doing being in the middle of you two.
-鲍比  -他人呢
- Bobby. - Where is he?
-现在不合适  -你个混蛋
- Hey, now's not the time. - You son of a bitch.
你凭什么认为你可以这样闯进我们的生活
You think you can just walk into our lives
就这么揭开旧伤疤
and--and rip open old wounds?
你们的生活  你最好在我做出什么
Your lives? You better get the hell out of my face
让你后悔的举动前赶紧走
before I do something that you'll regret.
你已经做了让我后悔的事
You already did something I regret
我就不该让你和你妈妈那样说话
by talking to your mother the way you did.
那个女人在背着我父亲和你睡在一起时
That woman gave up the right to be called my mother
就放弃了当我母亲的权利
when she got together with you behind my father's back.
也许你不把她当母亲了
Well, maybe you don't consider her to be your mother,
但她是我妻子
but she's my wife,
如果别人那样对她说话
and if anyone else spoke to her the way you did,
我早放倒他们了
they'd be on the floor right now.
你想跟我动手
You want to take a swing at me?
-哈维  哈维  -别  还别拦我
- Harvey, Harvey-- - No, no, no.
让他好好发泄一下
Let him get it out of his system,
因为我自己也很想发泄
'cause I know I want to get it out of mine.
我不是来打架的  哈维
I didn't come here to fight, Harvey.
我来是告诉你
I came here to tell you
我从来没见过你妈妈
I've never seen your mother more excited
像今晚出门见你时那么激动过
than when she was heading out to have dinner with you.
她终于要和她的儿子和好了
She was finally gonna get to reconnect with her son.
你却彻底毁了她的好心情
And then you pulled the rug out from underneath her.
是你夺走了她的喜悦
You took that excitement away.
所以这次你走了  就别再回来了
So, when you leave this time, just stay gone,
因为事实是
because the truth is,
这个家没有你过得更好
this family works better without you.
瑞秋  我需要你帮忙
Rachel, I need you to help me with something,
-而且很急  -什么事
- and I need it quickly. - What is it?
泰迪・道尔需要
Teddy Doyle needs to access
查看他为了避税
the proceeds from the sale of his company
放入信托的交易收入
that were put in trust to avoid taxes,
还不能因此触发税务检查
and he needs to do it without triggering those taxes.
路易  你开玩笑吗  我们不在迪拜
Louis, are you kidding? This isn't Dubai.
他的要求根本不可能
He's not gonna be able to do that.
我知道  但无论如何都要做到
I know that, but I need him to be able to anyway.
把文件给我
Give me the file.
-我会想出办法的  -谢谢
- I'll figure something out. - Thanks.
我为你骄傲  路易
I'm proud of you, Louis.
-为什么  -泰迪・道尔是哈维的客户
- For what? - Teddy Doyle is Harvey's client.
我听说了你们的事
And I heard about your thing.
所以  这意味着你原谅他了
So this must mean that you forgave him.
是的
I did.
想到办法马上告诉我
Bring that to me as soon as you have something.
迈克  哈伯曼的案子我有个问题
Hey, Mike, I got a question about the Haberman case.
他丢了工作  他们要收回他的车
He lost his job. They're taking his car.
-我在想办法  -你需要重申协议
- I'm trying-- - You need a reaffirmation agreement.
-待会儿再说好吗  -好
- Can I help you in a minute? - Yeah.
好
Great.
各位  能听我说两句吗
Hey, everyone, can you listen up for a sec?
玛莉莎
Marissa...
不会太久
this won't take long.
纳森向大家介绍我时
When Nathan introduced me,
说我曾在皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所工作
he told you that I used to work at Pearson Specter Litt.
但他没告诉你们  我为什么不在那儿工作了
What he didn't tell you is why I don't work there anymore.
而其中的原因
And the reason isn't
不是我没法回去当公司律师
that I couldn't hack it as a corporate lawyer.
而是我根本就不是律师
It's because I wasn't a lawyer at all.
大家看一下
Here, read that.
这是我的故事
That is my story.
我做的事情
That's what I did.
文章里的每一字都属实
Every word of these articles is true.
我根本就不应该去皮尔逊-斯佩克特
I never should have been at Pearson Specter.
但没有律师资格  并不是
But not being a lawyer isn't the only reason
我不该去那儿的唯一原因
I didn't belong there.
我之所以
You see, the whole reason
想成为一个律师
that I wanted to be a lawyer in the first place
就是为了帮助每一天
was so that I could help the kind of people
来到这家诊所的人们
that come into this clinic every single day.
我以为你们都知道我的事
Now, I thought you all knew this,
但我发现原来你们不知道
but it's clear to me now that you don't.
纳森是想要保护我
Nathan wanted to protect me,
但是
but...
我宁愿用事实换来你们的尊重
I'd rather have you respect me.
如果哪位还有问题
If any of you have any questions at all,
可以来找我谈
please come talk to me about it.
如果没有  大家就赶紧回去工作
If not, let's get back to work.
迈克
Mike.
你不必这么做
You didn't have to do that.
我应该
Yeah, I did.
你还没走
You're still here.
我的航班还有两小时才起飞
My flight isn't for another two hours.
我可没打算被那个混蛋轰走
I wasn't gonna let that asshole drive me away.
哈维  昨晚鲍比说的话
Listen, Harvey, about what Bobby said last night--
你不必为他找借口  马库斯
You don't need to make excuses for him, Marcus.
我不是在找借口
Oh, I'm not making excuses.
我只是告诉你
I'm telling you he had every right
他有资格那么说
to say what he said to you.
难以置信  你现在支持他了
I don't believe this. You're on his side now?
我支持的是我的家庭
The only side I'm on is my family's--
那个你一直都不参与的家庭
the family that you've never been a part of.
马库斯  别这样
Marcus, come on.
你知道告诉一个五岁的孩子
Do you know what it's like to tell a five-year-old
为什么奶奶和哈维伯父
why Grandma and Uncle Harvey
无法共处一室的感觉吗
can't be in the same room together?
因为你让我处于的就是这种境地
Because that's the position you put me in
年复一年
year after year.
这里有完满的生活
There's a whole life going on here
而你并不是其中一份子
that you're not even a part of.
你以为我不知道自己错过了什么
You think I don't know what I've missed?
我说的不只是生日  哈维
I'm not just talking about birthdays, Harvey.
我几年前旧病复发
I got sick again, couple years ago.
什么
What?
-你为什么不告诉我  -我为什么要告诉你
- Why didn't you tell me? - Why would I?
要我生病的同时面对你们的争吵吗
So that we could have this at the same time?
-马库斯  -停  听我说
- Marcus-- - No, listen to me.
你知道凯蒂带我去化疗时  是谁在帮忙吗
You know who helped out when Katie was taking me to chemo?
是妈妈每晚做饭
Mom made dinner every night.
是鲍比每天送孩子们上学
Bobby took my kids to school every day,
也就是说
which means...
虽然对你来说他们很可恶  但对孩子来说
while they might be monsters to you, to my kids,
他们就是爷爷和奶奶
they're Grandma and Grandpa.
你可能不愿意他们把鲍比当爷爷
And you might not like that shit coming from Bobby,
但事实如此  哈维
but it's the truth, Harvey...
无论你想不想听
whether you want to hear it or not.
有空吗
Do you have a minute?
当然
Of course.
很抱歉我误解了你
I'm sorry that I misjudged you.
没事
It's okay.
就像我说的  我们是一个队伍的
Like I said, we're on the same team.
确实  我也不该承诺索菲亚
We are, and I also should not have promised Sofia
我们一定赢
that we would win.
但我要说我会一直想办法
But I told you that I wouldn't stop looking for a way
帮她保住住处
to keep her in her home,
而且我也找到了
and I think I found one.
玛莉莎  无论你
Marissa, it doesn't matter
找到什么法律根据
what kind of legal basis you've got.
如果她不能及时付房租
If she can't pay her rent in the meantime--
这正是我要说的  特洛伊诉萨福克案
That's what I'm talking about--Troy v. Suffolk.
只要我们能证明她曾试图跟房东说过
As long as we can prove that she tried to tell the landlord
-供暖问题  -是的  但我们没法证明
- about the heat-- - Yeah, but we can't prove it.
她没有写下来
She doesn't have it in writing.
如果有电话记录就能证明
We can if we use the phone records.
通话记录不能作为证据
Phone records aren't proof of a complaint.
是不能  但如果一个人连续两个月
No, but the only people who call their landlord
每周都给房东打三次电话
three times a week for two months
那这个人一定是有东西要修理
are people who have a problem that needs fixing.
然后我们就可以拿出旅馆收据
Then we enter the motel receipts
和购买取暖器的收据
and the receipts for the space heaters
来抵付要交的租金
as substitution for rent paid.
他不仅无法驱逐她
And not only can he not evict her,
还不能收她的房租
she doesn't have to pay back rent.
我们只要说服法庭
We just need to convince the court
接受通话记录就可以了
to accept these phone records.
问题是我们不能说服法庭做任何事
The problem is we can't convince the court of anything.
我还不是律师
I'm not a lawyer yet,
我本来希望你能  但是
and I was hoping you could do it, but then...
没关系
It's okay.
我能找到这样的人
I've got just the person.
哈维
Harvey.
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
那要看你为什么来
Depends on why you're here.
我来为我昨晚的表现道歉
I'm here to apologize for the way I acted last night.
因为鲍比找过你了
Is this 'cause Bobby came to see you?
不是  因为马库斯生病了
No, it's because Marcus got sick,
是你一直在照顾他  他从没跟我说过
and you took care of him, and he couldn't even tell me that.
-哈维  -我很生气
- Harvey-- - I'm so angry.
我不想再生气了
I don't want to be angry anymore,
但我不知怎么样停下来
but I don't know how to stop.
那我要说我非常抱歉
Then let me say how sorry I am
给你带来这么多伤痛
for all the pain that I have caused you.
你不必跟我说你有多抱歉
You don't need to tell me how sorry you are.
但是我要说
Yes, I do.
哈维  过去二十年来的事
Harvey, we both may have played a part
我们都有责任
in the last 20 years,
但我是一个成年人
but I was an adult,
把你置于那种境地
and I put you in that position.
过去的每一天
And not a day goes by
我都清楚你为何恨我
that I don't understand why you hate me.
我是你的母亲
I was your mother.
我本该保护你
I was supposed to protect you...
而不是伤害你
not scar you.
哈维
Harvey...
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我不恨你  妈妈
I don't hate you, Mom.
我恨你做过的事  可能永远都恨
I hate what you did, and I probably always will,
但我不恨你
but I don't hate you.
这我能接受
I'll take that.
怎么了
What is it?
没什么  只是
It's nothing. It's...
只是  我在墙上挂了你的画
it's just, I had your painting on my wall
挂了这么久  我刚刚意识到
for the longest time, and I just realized...
我有多怀念它
how much I missed it.
我爱你  哈维
I love you, Harvey.
我也爱你  妈妈
I love you, too, Mom.
法官大人
Your Honor,
我的当事人是带着两个孩子的单身妈妈
my client is a single mother with two small children.
我的狗还是拉布拉多猎犬呢
And my dog is a Labrador retriever.
唯一相关的事实是
But the only thing that's relevant here
他的当事人欠了三个月房租
is that his client hasn't paid her rent in three months.
但她不付房租的原因则是
And the reason she hasn't paid it is because
整个冬天
she's had no heat
房子都没暖气  还有扇窗户坏了
and a broken window all winter,
虽然她已经反复要求修理了
despite repeated requests for repairs.
但这些要求没有形成任何文件记录
There's absolutely no documentation of any such request.
这不是真的  我当事人在两个月间
That's not true. My client called her landlord
给房东打了20次电话
20 times over the course of two months,
这可以从她的通话记录中看出
as you can see from her phone records.
那不能证明任何问题
That's not proof of anything.
那证明你的当事人跟我的当事人有过通话
It's proof your client spoke to mine
每次大概两分钟
for an average of two minutes per call,
当然不会是谈论天气
and it wasn't to talk about the weather.
法官大人  格雷迪先生
Your Honor, Mr. Grady gave me
在20分钟前才给我这些没意义的证据
a copy of this nonsense 20 minutes ago,
他还专门承认这些与本案不相关
and he specifically agreed it wasn't relevant.
她在说谎
That--that is a lie.
是吗  因为我有一条通话记录
Really? Because I have a phone record
是10分钟前我打给你的
of a two-minute call that I made to you
时常大概两分钟
ten minutes ago.
你可能是打给我了  但我们没谈那个
You may have called me, but we didn't talk about that.
是的  我打电话给你
That's right. Just because I called you
并不能说明我们谈了什么
doesn't mean I can prove what we talked about.
法官大人  她打了20次
Your Honor, she called 20 times.
对  或许是要解释她迟交房租的原因呢
Yeah, probably to say why her rent was late,
因为她从未支付
because she never paid it.
但我们无法知道
But we won't know that
因为她的要求从未写在纸面上
because we don't have it in writing,
而法庭要求的  就是纸面记录
which is what the court requires.
法官大人  我需要...
Your Honor, I need...
我请求一点时间与我上司协商
I'd like to request time to confer with my supervisor.
上司  他可是个律师
His supervisor? He's a lawyer.
-你得帮他  -我做不到
- You have to help him. - I can't.
我...需要一点时间整理思路
I just need a minute to--to gather my thoughts.
这算什么  学前教育圈吗
What is this, preschool circle time?
法官大人  那位女士没有支付房租
Your Honor, the woman didn't pay her rent.
现在到了支付期限
The deadline is now.
我们申请  如果明早十点没有收到支票
We are requesting permission to evict
则法庭允许将其驱逐
if we don't have a check by 10:00 a.m. tomorrow.
-法官大人  拜托  -她会失去她的家
- Your Honor, please. - She's gonna lose her home.
时间到了  律师  批准申请
Time's up, counselor. Permission granted.
哈维  你在这里做什么
Harvey, what are you doing here?
什么时候回来的
When did you get back?
十分钟前
Ten minutes ago.
怎么样
How'd it go?
很顺利
It went well.
我很高兴
I'm glad.
其实  我需要你帮点忙
As a matter of fact, I need your help with something.
什么事都可以
Anything.
但你得先去做一件事情
But there's something you have to do first.
-罗斯先生  -普莱斯小姐
- Mr. Ross. - Miss Price.
我有话想跟你说  你有时间吗
I wanted to talk to you. Do you have a minute?
不太有
Not really.
他们明天就来了  我在打包  还有...
They're coming tomorrow. I've been packing, and--
他们不会来的
They're not coming.
三千六百美金
$3,600?
应该够支付你
Should be enough to cover your rent
近三个月的房租了
for the last three months.
-我不明白  -法律诊所有基金
- I don't understand. - The clinic has a fund
帮人度过这种情况
to help with this kind of thing.
我们一直都在这么做
We do it all the time.
但这是你个人签的
But this is from you.
从我账户支付能快一点
It's just quicker to do it from my account--
你明白的  手续里繁文缛节太多
you know, red tape and all that.
-我不知道说什么了  -说你明早第一件事
- I don't know what to say. - Say you'll take that
就是把它拿给你的房东
to your landlord first thing in the morning.
如果他们除了给你写收据还做了什么事情
And if they do anything but give you a written receipt,
第一时间打给我
you call me right away.
我会的  谢谢你
I will. Thank you.
-你回来了  -是的
- You're back. - I am.
我听说你替我打理了我的客户
And I heard you took care of my client.
谢谢  路易
Thanks, Louis.
不客气  我们是合作伙伴
You're welcome, but we're partners,
他们都是我们共同的客户
and they're all our clients.
是的
They are.
路易  我说你没有准备好做管理合伙人
Louis, I didn't mean it when I said
那不是真心的
you weren't ready to be managing partner.
不  你是真心的
Yes, you did.
或许是  但事实是
Maybe I did, but the truth is,
我也没准备好
I'm not ready either.
我们一起做临时管理合伙人怎么样
What do you say we both act as interim managing partners?
我很荣幸
I'd be honored.
在我看来  我们要做的第一件事是
It seems to me, the first order of business is,
律所名称怎么办
what are we gonna do about the name of the firm?
我不知道你怎么想的
I don't know about you, but...
但我觉得我们还是不改了
I think we should keep it exactly the same.
我也这么想
Me too.
谁都不知道
I mean, you never know
她什么时候会想回来  对吧
when she's gonna want to come back, right?
没错  谁都不知道
No, Louis. You never know.
你俩还在这儿干什么呢
What are you two still doing here?
我们还有十二小时
We've still got 12 hours.
我们不会停止
We're not going to stop
帮助索菲亚保住公寓的
trying to keep Sofia in her apartment.
好样的
Good for you.
但你们不必今晚做了
But you don't have to do it tonight.
她获得了一点宽限的时间
Turns out she got a little grace period.
怎么会
How did she get that?
当你在乎你的当事人时
It's amazing what you can do
你做的事情会出乎意料
when you care about your clients.
那我猜我们明早第一件事
Then I guess first thing tomorrow,
就是做下一步的规划
we should plan our next move.
我想是的
I guess we should.